Dunya Ramicova Costume Design Collection MSS.004
University of California, Merced Library
Dunya Ramicova Costume Design Collection
1976-2015
University of California, Merced Library
MSS.004
147 Boxes
1007 Folders
Costume designs and illustrations by Dunya Ramicova, Professor Emeritus at UC Merced.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Dunya Ramicova was born in the former Czechoslovakia in 1950. She immigrated to the United States in 1968. She studied at The Goodman School of Drama and The Yale School of Drama She has designed costumes for more than 150 productions of theater, opera, ballet, dance, film and television in the United States and Europe.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes the life's work of costume designer Dunya Ramicova.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dunya Ramicova, 2013.
Costume design
- Illustrations and Renderings, 74 Boxes
  - I Lombardi alla Prima Crociata
    Scope and Contents
    Contains ninety drawings for the production of I Lombardi alla Prima Crociata, directed by Mark Lamos and produced by The Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY.
    Custodial History
    Gift of Dunya Ramicova, 2015
  - The Fairy Queen
    One hundred nineteen illustrations for the production of The Fairy Queen, directed by David Pountney and produced by The English National Opera.
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle
    Thirty three illustrations for The Caucasian Chalk Circle, directed by Peter Lackner and produced by Dramatic Arts Department, University of California, Santa Barbara.
  - Ah, Wilderness!
    Twenty seven illustrations for the production of Ah, Wilderness! directed by Daniel J. Sullivan and produced by Vivien Beaumont Theater at the Lincoln Center for Performing Arts.
  - Windows
    Fifty three illustrations for Windows, directed by Robert Egan and produced by the Mark Taper Forum, Los Angeles, CA.
    Gift if Dunya Ramicova, 2015
  - Ivanov
    Fifteen illustrations for the production of Ivanov, directed by Francesca Zambello and produced by Glimmerglass Opera and New York City Opera.
  - Griselda
    Eleven illustrations for the production of Griselda, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by the Santa Fe Opera.
  - Nixon in China
    Seventy seven illustrations for the production of Nixon in China, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Houston Grand Opera, Brooklyn Academy of Music, Kennedy Center for Performing Arts, De Nederlandse Opera, Los Angeles Opera, Frankfurt Opera, Maison de la Culture, English National Opera, and The Metropolitan Opera.
  - Iphigenie En Tauride
    Forty one illustrations for the production of Iphigenie En Tauride, directed by Francesca Zambello and produced by Glimmerglass Opera and the New York City Opera.
  - The Voyage
    Seventy illustrations for the production of The Voyage, directed by David Pountney and produced by The Metropolitan Opera.
  - Platonov
    Six illustrations for the production of Platonov, directed by Nikos Psacharopolous and produced by the Williamstown Theater Festival.
  - The Inspector General
    Tes illustrations for the production of The Inspector General, directed by Peter Sellars.
    Gift od Dunya Ramicova, 2015
  - Major Barbara
    Twenty illustrations for the production of Major Barbara, directed by Richard Lloyd and produced by the Yale Repertory Theater.
  - Citizen Tom Paine
    Forty eight illustrations for the production of Citizen Tom Paine, directed by James Simpson.
  - Marriage
    Fourteen illustrations for the production of Marriage, directed by Andrei Belgrader.
  - Childe Byron
    Eleven illustrations for the production of Childe Byron, directed by Geoffrey Pywell and produced by the Dramatic Arts Department University of California, Santa Barbara.
  - Heartbreak House
    Twenty one illustrations for the production of Heartbreak House, directed by Alvin Epstein and produced by the Yale Repertory Theater.
  - The Misanthrope
    Nineteen illustrations for the production of The Misanthrope, directed by Mark Lamos.
  - As You Like It
    Thirty two illustrations for the production of As You Like It, directed by Mark Lamos and produced by the Hartford Stage Company.
  - Aida
    Ninety three illustrations for the production of Aida, directed by David Pountney and produced by Bayerische Staatsoper.
  - La Clemenza di Tito
    Nineteen illustrations for the production of La Clemenza di Tito, directed by Stephen Wadsworth and produced by the Houston Grand Opera, Canadian National Opera, and Scottish National Opera.
  - The Gospel According to the Other Mary
    Seventy two illustrations for the production of The Gospel According to the Other Mary, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Los Angeles Philharmonic.
  - The Rake's Progress
    Eighteen illustrations for the production of The Rake's Progress, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Theatre Musical de Paris-Chatelet
  - The Tempest
    Thirty one illustrations for the production of The Tempest, directed by Mark Lamos.
  - Alcina
    Twenty two illustrations for the production of Alcina, directed by Stephen Wadsworth and produced by Royal Opera House at Covent Garden.
  - The Devil's Disciple
    Nine illustrations for the production of The Devil's Disciple, directed by Stan Wojewodski and produced by Williamstown Theater Festival.
  - The Seagull
    Twenty nine illustrations for the production of The Seagull, directed by Robert Sanford Brustein and produced by Yale Repertory Theater.
  - Sganarelle
    Twenty five illustrations for the production of Sganarelle, directed by Andrei Serban and produced by Yale Repertory Theater.
  - Jenufa
    Seven illustrations for the production of Jenufa, directed by Stephen Wadsworth and produced by the Seattle Opera.
  - Ghost Sonata
    Twenty one illustrations for the production of Ghost Sonata, directed by Andrei Serban and produced by Yale Repertory Theater.
  - Oedipus & The Symphony of Psalms
    Thirty two illustrations for the production of Oedipus & The Symphony of Psalms, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Salzburger Festspiele.
  - Barbarians
    Nineteen illustrations for the production of Barbarians, directed by David Jones and produced by the Brooklyn Academy of Music.
  - The Duchess of Malfi
    Thirty illustrations for the production of The Duchess of Malfi, directed by Petr Micka.
  - Mr. Puntilla and His Man Matti
    Thirteen illustrations for the production of Mr. Puntilla and His Man Matti, directed by Ron Daniels and produced by Yale Repertory Theater.
  - Tales from the Vienna Woods
    Five illustrations for the production of Tales from the Vienna Woods, directed by Keith Hack and produced by Yale Repertory Theater.
  - The Marriage of Figaro
    Seven illustrations for the production of The Marriage of Figaro, directed by Peter Sellars.
  - Don Juan
    Sixteen illustrations for the production of Don Juan, directed by Liviu Ciulei.
  - Peer Gynt
    Eight illustrations for the production of Peer Gynt, directed by Nikos Psacharopolous.
  - Lady In the Labyrinth
    Nineteen illustrations for the production of Lady In the Labyrinth, directed by Jane Ridley.
  - Bal
    Fifteen illustrations for the production of Bal, directed by Gregory Mosher and produced by Goodman Theater.
  - Hercules
    Twenty nine illustrations for the production of Hercules, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Lyric Opera of Chicago.
  - Dr. Atomic
    Forty eight illustrations for the production of Dr. Atomic, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by San Francisco Opera, De Nederlandse Opera, and Chicago Lyric Opera.
  - The Peony Pavilion
    One illustration for the production of The Peony Pavilion, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Wiener Festwochen, MC 93 Bobingy, Barbican Center, and Cal Performances.
  - Saint Francois D'Assisie
    Nineteen illustrations for the production of Saint Francois D'Assisie, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Salzburger Festspiele and L'Opera de Paris.
  - The Flying Dutchman
    Thirteen illustrations for the production of The Flying Dutchman, directed by Stephen Wadsworth and produced by the Seattle Opera.
  - The Electrification of the Soviet Union
    Twenty one illustrations for the production of The Electrification of the Soviet Union, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Glyndebourne Festival Opera.
  - Love's Labor Lost
    Twenty six illustrations for the production of Love's Labor Lost, directed by Mladen Kieslov.
  - Grownups
    Four illustrations for the production of Grownups, directed by John Madden.
  - The Pretenders
    Fourteen illustrations for the production of The Pretenders.
  - Emmeline
    Thirty one illustrations for the production of Emmeline, directed by Francesca Zambello.
  - The Recruiting Officer
    Twenty three illustrations for the production of The Recruiting Officer, directed by Lair Williamson.
  - Luisa Miller
    One hundred twenty six illustrations for the production of Luisa Miller, directed by Francesca Zambello.
  - Pride and Prejudice
    Thirty illustrations for the production of Pride and Prejudice, directed by Jon Jory.
  - Bach Cantata 199
    Three illustrations for the production of Bach Cantata 199, directed by Peter Sellars.
  - An American Tragedy
    Sixty five illustrations for the production of An American Tragedy.
  - Fidelio
    Sixteen illustrations for the production of Fidelio, directed by Stephen Wadsworth.
  - An Attempt At Flying
    Eleven illustrations for the production of An Attempt At Flying, directed by Mladen Kieslov and produced by Yale Repertory Theater.
  - Don Giovanni
    Two illustrations for the production of Don Giovanni, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Orf and Mediascope Productions.
  - The Death of Klinghoffer
    Thirteen illustrations for the production of The Death of Klinghoffer, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Theatre de la Monnai, Opera de Lyon, Glyndebourne Festival Opera, Wiener Festwochen, San Francisco Opera, Los Angeles Opera, and Brooklyn Academy of Music.
  - Man is Man
    Three illustrations for the production of Man is Man, directed by Ron Daniels.
  - The Father
    Ten illustrations for the production of The Father, directed by Robert Brustein.
  - Cabinet of Dr. Ramirez
    Two illustrations for the production of Cabinet of Dr. Ramirez, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Mediascope Productions.
  - Fools
    Eight illustrations for the production of Fools, directed by Walton Jones and produced by Alaksa Repertory Theater.
  - The House of Bernarda Alba
    Eight illustrations for the production of The House of Bernarda Alba.
  - The Mikado
    Eight illustrations for the production of the Mikado, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Lyric Opera of Chicago.
  - Cosi Fan Tutte
    One illustration for the production of Cosi Fan Tutte.
  - Hang on to Me
    Sixteen illustrations for the production of Hang on to Me, directed by Peter Sellars.
  - Candida
    Seven illustrations for the production of Candida, directed by Austin Pendletown and produced by Williamstown Theater Festival.
  - Landscape of the Body
    Nine illustrations for the production of Landscape of the Body, directed by Robert Falls.
  - Children of the Sun
    Eleven illustrations for the production of Children of the Sun, directed by Nikos Psacharopolous and produced by Williamstown Theater Festival.
  - On the Verge, Or the Geography of Yearning
    Eight illustrations for the production of On the Verge, Or the Geography of Yearning, directed by Mark Lamos and produced by Hartford Stage Company.
  - Uncle Vanya
    Ten illustrations for the production of Uncle Vanya, directed by Lloyd Richards.
  - La Ronde
    Eleven illustrations for the production of La Ronde, directed by David Trainer and produced by Williamstown Theater Festival.
  - The Hunchback of Notre Dame
    Five illustrations for the production of The Hunchback of Notre Dame, directed by James Lapin.
  - Xerxes
    Nine illustrations for the production of Xerxes, directed by Stephen Wadsworth.
  - Giulio Cesare
    One illustration for the production of Giulio Cesare, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Opera Theater of Boston.
  - Le Grande Macabre
    One illustration for the production of Le Grande Macabre, directd by Peter Sellars and produced by Salzburger Festspiele.
  - Tannhauser
    Two illustrations for the production of Tannhauser, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Lyric Opera of Chicago.
  - Curse of the Starving Class
    Thirteen illustrations for the production of Curse of the Starving Class.
  - Bloody Poetry
    Eight illustrations for the production of Bloody Poetry, directed by Lynne Meadow.
  - Tonight at Eight Thirty/ Ways and Means
    One illustration for the production of Tonight at Eight Thirty/ Ways and Means, directed by Ellis Rabb.
  - Hedda Gabler
    Eleven illustrations for the production of Hedda Gabler, directed by Daniel Sullivan.
  - El Nino
    Four illustrations for the production of El Nino, directed by Peter Sellars.
  - The Resistible Rise of Arturo Ui
    Fifteen illustrations for the production of The Resistible Rise of Arturo Ui, directed by Frank Condon.
  - The Magic Flute
    Eight illustrations for the production of The Magic Flute, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by Glyndebourne Festival Opera.
  - Madame-de-Sade
    Nine illustrations for the production of Madame-de-Sade.
  - A Doll's House
    Thirty-three illustrations for the production of A Doll's House, directed by Lloyd Richards and produced by Yale Repertory Theater.
  - The Indian Queen
    Eight codex objects containing illustrations for the production of The Indian Queen, directed by Peter Sellars and produced by the Perm State P.I. Tchaikovsky Opera and Ballet Theater in 2013, and English National Opera in 2015.
  - Melons
    Nine illustrations for the production of Melons, directed by Gina Honegger and produced by Yale Repertory Theater in New Haven, CT.
  - The Abduction from the Seraglio
    Two illustrations for the production of The Abduction from the Seraglio, produced by Yale School of Drama Master of Fine Arts Third Year Master Class Project in New Haven, CT.
  - L'Aiglon
    One illustration for the production of L'Aiglon, produced by Yale School of Drama Master of Fine Arts Third Year Master Class Project in New Haven, CT.
  - Oversized Illustrations
    Contains oversized illustrations for the following productions: Platonov; The Voyage; Romeo and Juliet; Uncle Vanya.
  - Crime and Punishment
    10 illustrations for the production of Crime and Punishment, produced by Yale School of Drama Master of Fine Arts Third Year Master Class Project in New Haven, CT.
- Production Materials, Ephemera, and Process Notes, 66 Boxes
  - Box 77
    - I Lombardi - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Director Mark Lamos (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - I Lombardi - Photographs of Scene Design Model (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - I Lombardi - Preliminary Costume Plot (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - I Lombardi - Production Correspondence (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - I Lombardi - Preliminary Written Color Plot (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - I Lombardi - Costume Production Reference: Description of Hair and Make-up Design (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - I Lombardi - Costume Production Reference: Principles, Chorus, and Supernumeraries: Visual Research, Copies of Designs, Costume Lists, and Fabric Swatches (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - I Lombardi - Costume Production Reference: Principles, Chorus, and Supernumeraries: Final Costume Plot (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - I Lombardi - Pre-production Publicity (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - I Lombardi - Playbill (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - I Lombardi - Reviews (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Box 78
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Director David Chambers (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Play Script (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Production Contact List (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Production Rehearsal and Performance Calendar (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Production Correspondence (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Preliminary Costume Plot (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Color Plot (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Production Meeting Notes (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Costume Production Reference: Visual Research, and Preliminary Costume Lists for all Characters (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Costume Production Reference: (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Costume Count (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Costume Production Reference: Lists of All Clothing Components (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Costume Production Reference: Final Costume Plot (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Rehearsal Notes (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Production Tech Schedule: Stage Use – Load-in and Tech/Preview Week (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Final Tech Scene Breakdown (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Pre-production Publicity (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Playbill (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - The Intelligent Design of Jenny Chow - Reviews (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Box 79
    - Ah Wilderness - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Director Daniel Sullivan (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Ah Wilderness - Preliminary Costume Plot (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Ah Wilderness - Production Correspondence (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Ah Wilderness - Production Contact Sheet (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Ah Wilderness - Written Research (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Ah Wilderness - Visual Research (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Ah Wilderness - Costume Production Reference: Revised Costume Plot (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Ah Wilderness - Costume Production Reference: Preliminary Costume Lists (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Ah Wilderness - Costume Production Reference: Copies of Designs (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Ah Wilderness - Costume Production Reference: Final Costume Lists (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Ah Wilderness - Costume Production Reference: Costume Bids (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Ah Wilderness - Rehearsal Reports (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Ah Wilderness - Playbill (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Ah Wilderness - Reviews (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Box 80
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Director Stephen Wadsworth (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Written Research (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Costume Production Reference: Costume Lists (Houston Grand Opera and Scottish National Opera) (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Costume Production Reference: Fabric Swatches for Principles, Chorus and Supernumeraries (Houston Grand Opera and Scottish National Opera) (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Costume Production Reference: Fabric Swatches for Principles, Chorus and Supernumeraries (Houston Grand Opera and Scottish National Opera) (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Production Photographs (Houston Grand Opera) (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Costume Production Reference (Canadian National Opera): Costume List (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Pre-production Publicity (Houston Grand Opera) (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Playbill (Houston Grand Opera) (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Reviews (Houston Grand Opera) (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Pre-production Publicity (Scottish National Opera) (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Playbill (Scottish National Opera) (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Costume Production Reference (San Francisco Opera) (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Box 81
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Pre-production Publicity (San Francisco Opera) (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Playbill (San Francisco Opera) (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Reviews (San Francisco Opera) (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Director Stephen Wadsworth (New York City Opera) (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Costume Design Contract Proposal and Budget (New York City Opera) (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - New York City Opera Season Master Calendar 99/00 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Production Correspondence (New York City Opera) (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Costume Production Reference (New York City Opera): Copies of Designs, Costume Lists and Fabric Swatches for Principles, Chorus and Supernumeraries (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Costume Production Reference (New York City Opera): Copies of Designs, Costume Lists and Fabric Swatches for Principles, Chorus and Supernumeraries (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Pre-production Publicity (New York City Opera) (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Playbill (New York City Opera) (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - La Clemenza di Tito - Reviews (New York City Opera) (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Fidelio - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Director Stehen Wadsworth - Opera Thpeatre of Saint Louis (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Fidelio - Production Correspondence (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Fidelio - Visual Research (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Fidelio - Costume Production Reference (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - Fidelio - Playbill (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Fidelio - Reviews (Box 81, Folder 18)
  - Box 82
    - Citizen Tom Paine - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Director James Simpson (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Citizen Tom Paine - Production Contact List (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Citizen Tom Paine - Production Schedule (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Citizen Tom Paine - Costume Production Reference (The Philadelphia Company) (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Citizen Tom Paine - Playbill (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Citizen Tom Paine - Costume Production Reference (Sharome Enterprises): Costume Lists with fabric swatches for most characters (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Citizen Tom Paine - Costume Production Reference (Sharome Enterprises): Costume Bids (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - El Nino - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Peter Sellars (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - El Nino - Written Story Board of Stage Action and Film Action and Color (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - El Nino - Visual Story Board Color Plot (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - El Nino - Production Contact Sheet (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - El Nino - Production Correspondence (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - El Nino - Costume Production Reference: Principal Singers and Dancers (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - El Nino - Costume Production Reference: Color Plot for Chorus Costumes (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - El Nino - Costume Production Reference: Chorus Information Sheet (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - El Nino - Los Angeles Philharmonic Playbill and El Nino Libretto (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - El Nino - Reviews (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Notes from Collaborative Meetings with Director Kenneth Frankel (Box 82, Folder 18)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Production Cast List (Box 82, Folder 19)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Visual Research (Box 82, Folder 20)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Scene Breakdown (Box 82, Folder 21)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Written Research Notes (Box 82, Folder 22)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Written Color Plot (Box 82, Folder 23)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Costume Production Reference (Box 82, Folder 24)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Playbill (Box 82, Folder 25)
    - Pride and Prejudice - Reviews (Box 82, Folder 26)
  - Box 83